

### CONTACT

- +92-316-2300835
- ✓ farooqazizbaloch@gmail.com
- in linkedIn.com/in/farooq-aziz-b09b40223
- dev-farooq-portfolio.vercel.app
- github.com/farooq-aziz
- Karachi, Pakistan

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering**

Indus University | 2022

# Intermediate In Computer Science

Atta Shad Collage Quetta | 2016

#### **SKILLS**

- HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
- Bootstrap, Tailwind, MUI
- · React Js, Next Js
- GitHub, Firebase
- PSD, XD
- Payment Integration
- API Integration
- Form validation

#### LANGUAGES

- English
- Urdu

## **FAROOQ AZIZ**

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **PROFILE**

Skilled Front-End Developer with 3+ years of experience. I'm passionate about Branding and creating attractive Responsive Websites using HTML, CSS, JS & Bootstrap. To secure a responsible career opportunity to fully utilize my skills, while making a significant contribution to the success of the company.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Crystallite Digital Pvt, Karachi

2023 - PRESENT

Senior React JS Developer

- Developed and maintained advanced UIs with React.js and Next.js, focusing on reusability and performance optimization.
- Leveraged Next.js for server-side rendering and static site generation, enhancing SEO and load performance.
- Integrated RESTful APIs and GraphQL for dynamic data handling and real-time updates, enhancing responsiveness and engagement.

#### Crystallite Digital Pvt, Karachi

2022 - 2023

Senior Front-End Developer

- Created multiple responsive websites for mobile and desktop devices using HTML, CSS and JS as well as third-party libraries such as jQuery.
- Collaborated with UX/UI designers to translate wireframes and mockups into functional, visually appealing web interfaces.
- Mentored junior developers and led code reviews, promoting best practices and improving team productivity.

#### Fayba Technologies, Karachi

2021 - 2022

Front-End Developer

- Developed an interactive layout, using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to generate an improved user experience and ensure high-quality design and cross-browser compatibility.
- Developed and executed front-end development strategies, resulting in a 15% increase in website performance.
- Tested and debugged code to ensure compatibility and stability, resulting in a 15% reduction in website errors and improved website functionality.

#### CERTIFICATIONS

- Web & Mobile App Development Jawan Pakistan, Karachi
- HTML5 & CSS3 Pirple.com
- Certified Information Technology (CIT)
  Global Computer Institute, Karachi